《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我们的孩子现在可以违抗物理学定律
We have a kid who defied the laws of physics
和她的父母一起消遣
to hang out with her parents.
-融化  -冰霜杀手...
- Melt. - Killer Frost...
消失了
Is gone.
只有你遇到麻烦的时候
The only time you need your mother
才会需要你的母亲
is when you're in trouble.
我父亲的死亡证明
My father's death certificate.
签署证明的法医
The M.E. who signed off on it,
并不存在
he doesn't exist.
我现在知道了为什么她一直
Now I know why she never wants to leave
25年后  闪电侠仍未出现
不想离开她爸的身边却从来都不想在我身边
her dad's side and never wants to be by mine.
我的神速力没有了
I just lost my speed.
听着像是虫子
Sounds like an insect.
像是蝉
Like a cicada.
"蝉"是谁
Who's Cicada?
闪电侠博物馆
2032年
小时候
As a kid
闪电侠博物馆里有个地方
there was a part of the Flash Museum
我总是很害怕
that always scared me.
小孩害怕怪兽
I guess it's normal for children
大概是正常的吧
to be afraid of monsters.
但这只怪兽不同
But this monster was different.
没人知道他从哪来
No one knows where he came from,
他从哪获得了超能力
how he got his powers,
他是谁
who he is.
人们只知道他的外号
All that's known is his alias,
和死在他手里的人最后听到的声音
and the last sound his victim's hear.
但他的可怕不是因为这个
But that's not what makes him scary.
而是因为...
What makes him scary is...
你永远抓不住他
you never catch him.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第三集
我们永远抓不住他
We never catch him?
超女  传奇们
Supergirl, The Legends,
连刺客联盟都试过  但没人成功
even The League tried, but no one was successful.
大概是因为他能用那该死的匕首
Probably 'cause he can dampen everybody's powers
削弱别人的超能力
with that magic friggin' dagger.
并非所有超级英雄都是超能力者的
Not all superheroes are meta-humans though.
-那... -绿箭侠吗
- What about-- - Green Arrow?
他也试过一次  但...
Yeah, he tried too once, but...
所以我们要对付有超能力的开膛手杰克
So we're dealing with a meta-human Jack the Ripper.
刺激
Amazing.
你对他还有多少了解
What else do you know about him?
就是...
Just that he...
他很早了
he's early.
他很早了是什么意思
What do you mean he's early?
在我们那的历史里  蝉的第一个受害者
In my history, Cicada's first victim
是一个叫弗洛伊德·贝尔金的超人类
was a meta-human named Floyd Belkin.
他从来没有杀过路霸和方块
And he never killed Gridlock or Block.
那些是完全不同的受害者
They're completely different victims.
因为时间线变了
Because the timeline changed.
是的  现在他们都死了...
Yeah, and now they're both dead...
都是因为我
because of me.
我们没法预测
Okay, there's no telling
这一改变的连锁反应是什么
the ripple effect of this change
或是诺拉要回到什么样的未来
or what kind of future Nora's gonna return to.
我们要赶紧抓住这家伙
We gotta catch this guy fast.
抓一个未来的我们都抓不住的家伙吗
You mean catch the guy that future us can't catch?
好吧  这么一比打败思考者还真容易
Right, I thought beating The Thinker was hard.
各位  是乔  中城警局在市里需要帮忙
Guys, it's Joe. CCPD needs help downtown.
-好  我去  -不了  我去吧
- Okay, I got it. - No, I'll--I'll do it.
-你确定吗  -嗯  我去解决
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I got it.
你们留在这里解决
You guys stay here and deal with
这个超能力连环凶手
the meta serial killer.
各位  我们肯定有办法的
Okay, guys, look, we got this.
我们搜查一下犯罪现场
Let's just canvass some crime scenes,
采访几位目击者
interview some witnesses, and see if there's any
看看路霸和方块有没有共同的熟人
common acquaintances between Gridlock and Block.
我有个计划
I have a plan.
你...你这么快就有计划了
You--you've got a plan already?
我知道怎么补救了
I know how to fix this.
所有人都给我老实点
Now nobody try nothing funny.
这宝贝是太阳能的  碳排放量为零
This baby is solar with a zero carbon footprint.
我花了一整周在太阳下
I spent a week in the sun charging
用紫外线ABC波段给它充电
with U, V, A, B, and C!
所以你们最好别乱动
So y'all stay put.
我说过  用我自己的袋子
I told you, I brought my own bags.
-抱歉  -接受你的道歉
- Sorry. - Apology accepted.
别忘了还有一种绿色蔬菜
Don't forget the other kind of greens.
搞什么
What the hell?
别害怕  市民朋友们
Fear not, good citizens.
伸缩人在此
Elongated man is here.
我怎么觉得你们
Why do I feel like you're focusing
搞错重点了呢
on the wrong thing?
我刚救了你们...
I just saved you--
好吧  你们能不能...
okay, if you're gonna--
别发到网络上...别发...
just don't post--don't post--
我看见你发了
I saw you post it.
所以你的计划就是找威尔斯先生
So your plan is to contact Herr Wells?
没错
Yes, that's my plan.
我知道未来你们从没找某个威尔斯
I know in the future you guys never bring in a Wells
来帮你们抓住蝉
to help you catch Cicada.
所以如果要想有不同的结果...
So if you want a different result this time...
就得尝试新法子
I try something new.
这是个好主意
It's a great idea.
-并不是  -什么
- 'Cept it's not. - What?
这是个坏主意  如果你要找人合作
It's a terrible idea. If you're looking for cooperation,
相信我  他不是你要找的人
trust me, this is not your guy.
他就是个混蛋
He is just an asshat.
这话过分了  西斯科
That's way harsh, Cisco.
-什么  我过分  -对
- I'm sorry, I'm being harsh? - Yes.
那好  找他吧
Go ahead, call him.
等着来个怒气冲冲挑三拣四的人吧
See if you don't get a steaming pile of side-eye.
行
Okay.
闪电侠
The Flash.
等着看吧
Wait for it,
-我爱闪电侠  -什么
- I love The Flash. - What?
你是巴里·艾伦吧  跑得飞快  咻咻
Oh, you Barry Allen, yah? With the zoom, zoom,
能违背物理定律和重力
and defy the physics laws and gravity.
永远那么有型而又优雅
Always with some style and grace, yah.
多谢夸奖啊
Thanks, man.
那是小闪电侠  闪电侠的孩子
Das Kinder Flash. Child of the Flash.
显然  你继承了爸爸的道德品质
Obviously, you have your father's moral fiber, yah.
还继承了妈妈的智慧和古典美
And your mother's smarts, and classic beauty.
-哎哟  快别说了  -多谢  威尔斯先生
- Oh, my God. Stop. - Thank you, Herr Wells.
别谢他
No, don't thank him.
别信他的鬼话
Don't fall for this ruse.
这家伙明显是装的
Clearly this guy is putting on an act.
他就是个骗子
He's a charlatan.
但是你中伤我  背后给我捅刀子
But you hurt me, stab me in the back,
这人肯定是西斯科
this guy who must be Cisco.
-你知道我是谁  -别这么没礼貌
- You know who I am. - Hey, don't be rude.
好吗  不好意思
All right, look. Hey, I'm sorry.
我们需要你帮忙抓住超能力连环杀手
We need your help catching a meta-human serial killer.
我听说过这个蝉
Yeah, I have heard of this Cicada.
当然  我收到了小闪电侠的信息
Of course, the message already from Kinder Flash.
可惜我现在很忙
Unfortunately, I'm otherwise occupied,
这次没法帮你们了
unable to assist you at this time.
-不行吗  -不行
- You can't? - Nein.
但是更好的是
But, I have done one better
我打电话叫了能帮忙的人
and called someone who can.
这人是一个传奇
This man is a legend,
这人是所有多元宇宙中最伟大的侦探
this man is the greatest detective in all the Multiverse.
我在邮件里附上了他的坐标
So I've attached his coordinates
-你们可以看看  -好
- if you want to look at them. - Okay.
-看到了吗  -看到了
- Yah, do you see it? - Got 'em.
-很好  -西斯科
- Good. - Cisco.
西斯科啥  你们要我打开缺口把他带过来吗
Cisco what? You want me to breach him here?
-是的  -我刚被人在铁板上"煎"完
- Yeah. - Hello? I just got Benihana'd.
-有点疼  -抱歉
- Hurts a little bit. - Sorry.
不如用老办法打开缺口把他带过来吧
Why don't we just breach him here the old fashioned way?
谢谢你  很高兴见到你
Hey, man, thank you for this. This is great.
很荣幸能帮到闪电侠
Privilege and an honor to help The Flash, yah,
小闪电侠和爱瑞丝闪电侠
and Kinder Flash, and Iris Flash, yah.
拜  小闪电侠
Bye, Kinder Flash.
拜  威尔斯先生
Bye, Herr Wells.
真是个好人
Nice guy.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about, man?
-他人太好了  -他不...
- He's awesome. - He's not--
这样吧
You know what?
我们打开外推器
Let's just turn on the extrapolator
把这位大侦探接过来吧
and get this master detective out here.
我来了
Well...
我还以为你们的地球比我那冷
I imagine your Earth would be colder.
哈里森·歇洛克·威尔斯
Harrison Sherloque Wells
愿为您效劳
at your service.
我是来帮你们抓凶手的
I'm here to catch your killer.
中城图书馆
-巴里  他在干吗  -我不知道
- Barry, what is he doing? - I don't know.
-可能是调查犯罪现场的装备  -好了
- Maybe it's some kind of CSI kit? - Voila.
让他...
Shh. Just let him...
就是这个味
That's the stuff.
我们可以开始了
And now we can begin.
-是茶吗  -没错
- Tea? - That's right.
我们已经看你弄了二十分钟
We've been watching you for 20 minutes.
不客气
You're welcome.
-好品质是急不来的  -这就是浪费时间
- Cannot rush excellence. - This is a waste of time.
非常感谢你来一趟  "康伯巴奇"
Thank you very much for coming, Cumberbatch.
电视剧《神探夏洛克》主演
我相信你很希望我走吧
I'm sure you would like it if I took my leave, right?
可以有更多的时间从近期失恋中恢复过来
Could have more time to recover from your recent heartbreak.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
皮下黑眼圈瘀伤
Subcutaneous under-eye bruising,
说明你一直在哭
which indicates you've been crying.
脱皮说明你缺水
Flaky skin, which indicates dehydration,
也许是因为喝酒
probably from alcohol consumption.
借酒浇愁和以泪洗面只能说明一件事
Alcohol plus crying can only mean one thing.
你被人甩了
You have been dumped.
错  大侦探
Wrong, detective.
-我没被人甩  -没有吗
- I have not been dumped. - Oh, no?
那是双方共同做出的决定
It was a mutual decision, okay?
我和辛西娅  我们一起做了决定
Cynthia and I, we reached a decision together as a team.
当然了
Sure. Of course.
我连哭泣都没有
Okay, and I haven't been sobbing.
其实  上次哭是什么时候我都不记得了
In fact, I can't remember the last time I cried about it.
失陪
Excuse me.
我猜你就是那个极速者吧
You are the resident speedster, I presume?
-你怎么  -你喜欢用右脚来急停
- How did you-- - Who favors stopping on his right heel?
从你鞋子上的磨损能看得出
Can tell from the wear and tear on your footwear.
两只鞋边不齐
It's uneven.
这是你从你父亲那里继承的品质
A trait that you have inherited from your father.
但是你确实
Although you do share
更继承了你母亲的肢体语言
a little bit more body language with your mother,
从我来到这里起
who's been touching her left shoulder
她一直在摸自己的左肩
since I came around here.
-你有什么事瞒着我  -你说什么
- What are you hiding from me? - Excuse me?
我没隐瞒任何事
I am not hiding anything.
不不不  你有  是什么呢
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. Yes, you are, but what?
你摸了左肩  就好像
You have touched it, like...
有东西在那  然后又没了
it's something there, then gone again,
抹掉了什么东西  文身是吧
something removed. A tattoo, right?
没错  也许是前任留下的
Yes, perhaps from a former lover?
好了  这样吧
Okay! You know what?
我认为这个歇洛克已经证明了他自己
I think that this Sherloque has proven himself
我们应该开始找蝉了
and that we should start finding Cicada.
好极了  我们开始找蝉吧
Excellent. Let's find Cicada.
但首先  我的费用问题
But first, the question of my fee.
你要我们付费吗
You're charging us?
这次查案不是免费的吧
This service is not free, right?
我不为慈善事业工作
I don't work for charity.
我已经看得出这位年轻的医生
Can already tell the young doctor here
想要雇我调查另一件案子
is expecting to hire me for another case.
我瞄了一眼你的包
I saw you glance at your purse,
我很乐意助你解开疑团
and I'm happy to assist you in that mystery.
但首先  我想我们都同意
But first, I think we can all agree
像蝉这样的大反派
that a villain of Cicada's caliber...
需要一大笔费用
will require a substantial fee.
嗯
Yeah.
我去  这即使在未来这也不是小钱
Shrap, that's a lot of money even from when I from.
我的费用昂贵  但绝对物有所值
I'm very expensive, but very worth it.
你们怎么看
What do you think?
我们可以卖掉尖端科研实验室的一些囤货
I mean, we could sell off some of Star Labs stock.
-好棒  我们达成协议了  -嗯
- Yes! We have an agreement. - Yeah.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear that?
慌乱的脚步声  有人闯进来了
Sounds of these frantic steps, we're being approached
不是一个高大灵敏的男子
either by a tall, sensitive man, or...
就是一只惊恐的小长颈鹿
a frightened, baby giraffe.
我遇到麻烦了  各位
I got-- I got a problem here, guys, and I--
小长颈鹿你好啊
Hello, baby giraffe.
哈里  你好吗
Harry, how are you?
这位是歇洛克·威尔斯
This is Sherloque Wells.
-洛克  洛  克  -歇洛克
- Loque. "L-O-Q-U-E." - Sherloque.
歇洛克  我是法国人
Sherloque. I'm French.
-歇漏克是...  -洛克
- "Sher-lowk" here is-- - Loque.
要帮我们找到蝉
is gonna help us find Cicada.
棒  你是侦探吗
Oh, cool, so you're like a detective.
侦探  原来是粉丝
Oh, detective, the fans.
我应该给谁签名
Who should I make the autograph out to?
长颈鹿宝宝
Hello, little baby giraffe.
不是  不是  听着
Uh, no, no, no. I'm--I'm--listen.
我也是名侦探
I'm a detective as well.
是 没错
Yeah. Yeah.
那好吧
Ah, well...
[胡乱地说着法语]
真好  你也是名侦探
That's right, well, you're a detective.
那你最近解决了什么案子
What--what have you solved recently?
最最近的吗  我解决了
Most recently? I uncovered the case
雪佛兰盗窃案
of the stolen Chevy.
因帕拉之案
Of Impala.
有意思
Funny. Hmm.
这些看起来都挺有趣的
Very funny from the looks of things.
好吧  我是救了一群人质
Well, okay, so I saved all these hostages
但是其他人在谈论的都是这张照片
and--and all anybody can talk about is this picture,
你本想要鼓起勇气
最终鼓起来的只有你的肚子
然后就变成了流行梗  这下就...
and turned into a meme. And--and--it's--
这个  我觉得这城市里没人
this is--I just--I don't think anybody in this city
把我当回事
takes me seriously.
这城市里有一千四百万人
Oh, there's 14 million people in this city.
只有五十万人转发了这个
Only 500,000 have reposted this.
没错
Yeah.
那么  蝉
So, uh...Cicada?
蝉  是的
Cicada, yes.
我查看了你们的证据
I've reviewed your evidence
我知道要去哪找你们那杀手了
and I know where to find your killer.
来吧  咱们晚餐前搞定他  如何
So, shall we, let's get this done before dinner, right?
好了  出发吧
All right, allons-y.
别着急  小长颈鹿
Not so fast, baby giraffe.
两名侦探只会让事情变得复杂
Two detectives only complicates matters.
尤其是其中只有一位是大师
Especially when only one is a master.
所以你为什么不留在这里
So why don't you stay put?
你可以  吃点叶子  其他人跟我来
You can, bite the leaves. Everyone else, come with em.
[法语]
你还好吗
You okay? Hmm?
还好  我...
Oh, yeah. I'm--
我挺好的  我刚被
Yeah, I'm--I'm great. I just got shut down
尚格·云顿损了一通
by Jean-Claude Van Damme.
你知道蝉不是这里
You know Cicada's not the only mystery
唯一需要解决的谜团吧
around here that needs solving.
是
Yeah.
妈妈  我知道这听起来很疯狂
Mom, I know it sounds crazy,
但是我们认为有人伪造了爸爸的死亡证明
but we think someone forged Dad's death certificate.
你们有证据吗
Have you any proof?
没有  也不是  有类似的
No, well, yes, sort of.
这事很复杂  不过
It's complicated, but
我只是想告诉你一声
I just thought you should know.
-除非我已经知道了  -我没这么说
- Unless I already knew. - I didn't say that.
你就是为这而来的  对吗
It's why you're here, isn't it?
如果这是某种精心设计
If this is some elaborate,
可能有邪恶用意的掩盖
possibly nefarious cover-up,
就一定是妈妈干的
it must be mom's doing.
仿佛她从来没有
It's not like she's ever
从心底为你着想一样
had your best interests at heart.
你总是做这种事
You always do this.
我只想要了解真相
I just want to know the truth.
我认为这是我应得的
I think I deserve to know that.
那...
Is...
我爸爸是不是真的...
my dad even really--
凯特琳  你父亲死了
Caitlin, your father is dead.
如果你真心在乎我的感受
And if you care about my feelings at all,
你就放下这事吧
you'll just let this be.
谢了  妈妈  一如既往的快乐交流
Thanks, mom. Pleasure as always.
不要沉迷于过去
Don't become obsessed with the past.
你父亲也有这个缺点  这导致他走向毁灭
Your father had that flaw. It nearly led to his ruin
甚至是在他丧命之前
even before his death.
我想你认识出去的路
I trust you know the way out.
抱歉大老远过来什么都没查出来
I'm sorry we came all this way for no reason.
不  我很佩服  你妈妈很会撒谎
No, I'm impressed. Your mom is a really good liar.
我知道是她伪造的死亡证明
Yeah, I know she forged this death certificate.
只是  她永远不会告诉我们为什么
I just-She's never gonna tell us why.
我们撞到南墙了
We've hit a brick wall.
在你看到是墙的地方
Ah, but where you see a wall
本侦探看到的是没有把手的墙砖门
this detective sees a brick door with no handle.
我是说我知道怎么搞到我们需要的情报
What I mean is I know exactly how to get what we came for.
-你确定他在里边吗  -我很确定
- You sure he's in there? - I'm certain.
现在  你们的证物  虽然很粗略
Now, your evidence, while slight,
但也足够建立心理分析速写了
was enough to build a psychologic profile.
这是个躲藏在阴影中的男人
This is a man hiding in the shadows.
这是个被推到了
This is someone who's been pushed
社会边缘的人
to the peripheries of society,
而现在他独自坐在那里
and then now he sits alone
等待着出击的时机
waiting for the moment to strike.
所有这些  加上人口资料
All this, plus the census data
与他袭击地点交叉比照后
cross-referenced with the location of his attacks,
范围就缩减到一个名字上
and the profile narrows to one name...
大卫·赫希
David Hersch.
诺拉的计划没准真能起作用
Nora's plan might actually work.
一定会起作用
Well, it will work.
一旦进去  你们应该会看到个饵雷
Once inside, you should find a small booby trap.
我找到了
I found it.
我来弄
I'm on it.
现在是关键部分了
Here is the critical part.
那诱饵
It's a decoy.
抱歉  我没反应过来
Sorry. I got caught off-guard.
没了匕首就没能耐了  对吧
Not so tough without your dagger, huh?
我们抓到他了
We got him.
真是荒谬
That's ridiculous!
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你没有任何证据
You don't got anything on me!
-他听起来倒是很愤怒  -是啊
- Well, he sounds angry. - Yeah.
鉴证科检查了赫希的躲藏地
Forensics examined Hersch's hideout
他们找到了将他与
and they found evidence linking him
多起反政府炸弹案相关联的证据
to several anti-government bombings.
他干这事有段时间了
He's been doing it for a while.
-所以我们抓到他了  -我不知道
- So we got him. - I don't know.
他们没找到他的匕首
They didn't find any sign of his dagger
或是面具
or his mask.
爸爸  以现场调查员身份来说
Dad, one CSI to another
看看这些证据  好吗
look at the facts, okay?
歇洛克是多元宇宙中最棒的侦探
Sherloque is the best detective in the Multiverse.
他的速写带我们找到了大卫·赫希
His profile led us to David Hersch,
并且我们找到了大卫·赫希
and we found evidence that David Hersch
犯下多重谋杀的证据
is a mass murderer.
我们抓错人的几率能有多大
What are the chances that this isn't our guy?
-或许你说得对  -我们该庆祝下
- I mean, maybe. - Come on, we should celebrate.
好  我去召集所有人
Okay, I'm gonna gather everyone up,
弄点喝的
make some drinks,
然后我们可以在新客厅
and we can have our first party
-开首次派对  -我不知道  诺拉
- in the new lounge. - I don't know, Nora.
我...
I--
约瑟夫·韦斯特警探
Detective Joseph West.
你想要什么
What do you want?
结束我挑起的事
To finish what I started.
那个叫震波的超能力者
The meta-human called Vibe.
现在叫他来
Call him here now.
办不到  我不认识他
I can't. I don't even know him.
中城新闻图报
屋顶超能大战以拘捕终结
你想说什么
You were saying?
没错  他在帮助中城警局
Yes, I mean, he helps CCPD,
但是这不代表我有震波专线
but it's not like I have a Vibe phone
随时可以打电话给他
so I can just call him up.
他就是一个蒙面行善者
He's just a masked do-gooder
自己出现在犯罪现场的那种
that shows up at crime scenes.
这里也可能成为犯罪现场
This could be a crime scene.
当你说你有个计划的时候  拉尔夫
When you said you had a plan, Ralph,
我没想到你指的是非法入侵
I didn't mean you meant breaking and entering
我妈妈公司档案室
into my mother's company's files.
档案室
强化钢板
Reinforced steel.
这种时候我就格外想念冰霜杀手
It's times like this I really miss Killer Frost.
不要担心
Oh, don't you worry.
拉尔夫能搞定
Ralphie's got it.
好吧
Okay.
好的  马上就好
Yep. Almost there.
等一下  马上就搞定
Hang on. Yeah, almost got it.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
-怎么了  -激光
- What is it? - Lasers.
这个房间布满了激光
Rooms filled with lasers!
我的妈呀  我去
Holy snakies. Oh, my God.
这房间就像是让人痛苦的魔方
It's like a Rubik's Cube of pain.
我不知道密码
I don't know the code.
倒是试一下
Try something
你妈妈肯定
that your mother would--
凯特琳  肯定有什么有意义的数字
Caitlin! There's gotta be something.
成了
Got it.
你没事吧
You okay?
没什么是一加仑芦荟油不能治愈的
Nothing a gallon of Aloe won't fix.
找托马斯·斯诺这个名字
Look for the name Thomas Snow.
找到了
Jackpot.
这是什么
What is that?
这是我老爸以前和我玩的游戏
It's a game my dad and I used to play.
他以前会教我周期表  但是
He would teach me the periodic table, but...
他有时候会让我
he would let me make up
自己编造出虚构的化合物和元素
my own fictional compounds and elements.
怪咖鎓
Nerd-onium?
他常说  这样做会让我们变得更聪明
He used to say it's what made us so smart.
我们以前在一起过得很开心
We used to have so much fun together.
一起在后院捉虫
Catching bugs in the backyard,
用我们一起造的望远镜观察星群
looking at constellations through a telescope we built.
他教会了我很多关于科学和人生的事
He taught me so much about science and life.
给我亲爱的凯特琳
也许他还留下了什么要教你的事
Maybe he still has something left to teach you.
-这是什么  -是我爸爸写的信
- What is it? - It's a letter from my dad.
说是要...
Saying...
道别
goodbye.
这是自杀遗言
It's a suicide note.
酒饮  非常感谢你  女士
Alcohol, thank you, very much. Merci.
他来了
There he is.
爸  我们都准备好要庆祝了
Dad, we're all set to celebrate--
不行
No, hey, um.
实际上赫希不是蝉
Actually, Hersch isn't Cicada.
什么
What?
肯定是他
He has to be.
不是  我检查了蝉留在
No, I checked Cicada's boot print from
方块和路霸两个犯罪现场的脚印
both the Block and Gridlock crime scenes
比赫希的脚印要大三个码
and it's three sizes larger than Hersch's.
不是他
It's not him.
一定得是他
Well, of course it's him.
一直都是赫希
It's always Hersch.
每次我抓到的蝉  都是同一个人
Every time I capture Cicada it's always the same man.
等下  你以前抓到过他
Wait a minute, you've caught this guy before?
37次  我抓到过蝉37次
37 times. I've captured 37 Cicadas,
在37个不同的地球
37 different Earths,
每一次我试图抓到蝉
and every time I try to capture him
线索都一直指向地球上的大卫·赫希
trail always leads back to that Earth's David Hersch.
所以你说你创建的心理特征侧写
So this psychological profile that you created,
都是你瞎编的
you just made it up?
第一次的时候不是
Not, the first time.
但是接下来的36次  我就直接提出理论
Now the next 36, then I just trot it out there.
为了打动客户
You know, to impress the client,
然后  跳到结果
and then... Skip to the end.
我之前还觉得你是个糟糕的侦探
And here I thought you just a bad detective,
但是你不是糟糕
but you're not a bad detective.
你就是懒货
You're just a lazy one.
[法语]
我这不叫懒  叫有效率  好吗
I'm not lazy. I'm efficient, right?
不管怎么说  这些都不重要
Anyway, that's not the point!
重点是  没有理由相信这个地球上的蝉
The point's simply that there's no reason for the Cicada
是除了大卫·赫之外的任何人
of this Earth to be anyone other than David Hersch.
也许有一个理由
Well, there may be one reason.
是什么
What's that?
因为时间线
The timeline.
没错  自从诺拉来了之后
Yes, since Nora got here
事情的发展就有了变化
things have changed a bit.
对
Yeah.
不会吧  你肯定得
Oh, mais no, you must--
你们之前怎么不说
how can you not tell me this?
你们不把变量告诉我
How am I expected to operate
该让我怎么侦破案件啊
when you don't give me all the variables?
不知道  但是我们现在想的是
I don't know, but what we can expect
退款  所以
is a refund, so...
对
Yeah.
不行  不可能  钱都花完了
Oh, no, no, no. That money is long gone.
你说什么  花完了
What do you mean "It's gone"?
你一天之内就把钱花完了
You spent all that money in one day?
-对  -花哪儿了
- Right. - On what.
我的前妻  们
My ex-wife-ves..
我的前妻们  七次婚姻
Ex-wives. Seven marriages.
五个老婆  要付很多赡养费
Five wives. Lots of alimony.
这些不是重点  重点是
That's not the point! The point is simply
这不是我的错
this is not my fault.
这是你的错  你们该怪她
It's your fault. She is to blame.
时间线变化
Timeline variance.
爸
Dad.
你不能就因为一个鞋印
You're not gonna let Hersch off the hook
而放过赫希
because of a boot print.
他是个超能力者
He's a meta.
我们不知道这家伙会干什么
How do we know what this guy can do?
不是这么一回事
That's the other thing.
赫希身上没有暗物质读数
Hersch has no dark matter readings.
他不是超能力者
He's not a meta.
好了  记住  作为犯罪现场鉴证员
All right, remember. From one CSI to another,
我们需要关注事实  好吗
we have to look at the facts, right?
我们抓错了人
We got the wrong guy.
不  这次没有  你知道我们该做什么吗
No, not this time. You know what we should do?
我们该以防万一把他扔进管道监狱直到他开口
We should throw him in the pipeline for safe keeping until he talks.
我要去抓他了
I'm gonna go get him.
你要干什么  不许你去
Hey, what are you, no, you're not.
我们不能绑架警方拘留的嫌疑犯
We're not gonna kidnap a suspect in police custody.
如果你没明白错在哪里
If you don't see what's wrong with that,
你就不要插手了
you can sit this one out.
看来关于蝉的事情我们又得从头做起
Well, guess we're back to square one with Cicada.
是啊
Yeah.
希望拯救下一个受害人还不晚
Let's hope it's not too late to save his next victim.
你有一个美好的家庭  韦斯特警探
You have a lovely family, Detective West.
不给我想要的
By not giving me what I want,
把你的生活置于危险中
by putting your life in danger,
你这是赌上了他们的未来
you're gambling their future with you.
如果你知我所知
If you knew what I know,
你会更珍惜他们的
you'd cherish them more.
我是不会引震波进死亡陷阱的
I'm not luring Vibe into a death trap.
随你怎么威胁我
You can threaten me all you want.
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
我相信你
I believe you.
但是你应该害怕
But you should be.
还在纠结吗
Still swirling around up there?
我只是不懂诺拉
I just don't get Nora.
我以为她领会了我们的训练
I mean, I thought our training was sinking in.
她打败了方块  她确实在进步
She defeated Block. She was really making process.
而一眨眼  她却想闯入中城警局
And next thing I know, she wants to break into CCPD
绑架一个警方拘留的嫌疑犯
and kidnap a suspect in police custody.
就像是她想要
I mean, it's like she wants to
让赫希成为蝉
make Hersch Cicada.
巴里  你真的不懂她为什么执着吗
Barry, you really don't get why she's obsessed?
-等等  我应该懂吗  -好好想想
- Wait. Should I? - Think about it.
她自从来这里就一直听到
She's been hearing about the ripple effects
关于时间线的连锁反应
on the timeline since she got here
刚开始反应还比较小
and at first they were relatively small,
但是现在...
but now...
-蝉和...  -反应不再那么小了
- Cicada and... - It's not so small.
他是史上最坏的连环杀手
He's one of the worst serial killers in history,
现在因为诺拉...
and now because of Nora...
他出现得早了
he's here early.
而且是一个完全不同的人
And an entirely different person.
造成了一批完全不同的受害者
With an entirely different set of victims.
对于一个只想和从未谋面的父亲相处的女儿而言
That is a huge weight to bear for someone
需要承受巨大的压力
who just wanted to spend time with a dad she never knew.
她觉得非常愧疚  巴里
She feels really guilty, Barry.
她想要努力修补她的错误
She wants to try to fix her mistakes
不管有什么代价
whatever that takes.
听起来像是我认识的另一个极速者
Sounds like another speedster I know actually.
诺拉说监狱管道入口有紧急情况
Nora says there's an emergency in the pipeline intake.
你确定这是...
Are you sure that...
歇洛克
Sherloque.
确定  这里发生什么了
Yeah. What happened?
据我所知  这看起来像是
As far as I can tell it looks like
当融合电池进入临界状态时
he was in the wrong place
他正处在错误的位置
when this fusion cell went critical.
我觉得是没有放好位置
I think it wasn't placed in its cradle properly.
-化成灰了  -简直了
- Vaporized into ash. - What a way to go.
-恶作剧  -天呐
- Shenanigans. - Good grife!
我称之为恶作剧
I call shenanigans.
你们看  这里的这些电池
You see, these cells right here,
它们在一个冗余的级联电路里运行
they run in a redundant cascade circuit.
他们一开始就是这样给管道监狱供能的
That's how they power the pipeline,
所以如果其中一个电池炸开了
in the first place, so if one of them blew
它们就都会炸裂了
they all would have blown.
是啊  整个管道监狱都会爆炸的
Yeah, the whole pipeline would have exploded.
完全正确
Exactly right.
大吉岭  乌龙
Darjeeling, oolong.
茶叶
Tea leaves.
巴里  行行好去检查一下大楼
Barry, be a dear and check the building
看看有没有一只带着猪肉馅饼帽的黄鼠狼
for a weasel in a pork pie hat,
像你这么高  闻起来有点像肉汁乳酪薯条
about yay tall, smells vaguely of poutine.
告诉我
Tell me...
谁死了
who died?
找到了他和这个
Found him with this.
毫不意外
Of course, you did.
你觉得你可以就这么离开
So you thought you could just leave
去另一个地球  而不退款给我们吗
to another Earth without paying us back?
在我的第四个老婆身上奏效了
Worked on my fourth wife...
还有第六个
and my sixth.
同一个女人
Same woman.
好了  西斯科
Okay, Cisco,
也许是时候讨论一下
maybe it's time to have a talk
设立一个叫做债务人监狱的小地方了
about a little place called debtor's prison.
跟我来
Come with me.
-好的  -你让我想念绅士威尔斯了
- All right. - You make me miss Herr Wells.
跟我来
Come with me.
是我在带你
I'm--I'm taking you!
你还好吗
You okay?
还好  只是...
Yeah, yeah. It's just...
有一瞬间  我觉得是我把歇洛克请到这来
for second I thought me inviting Sherloque here
才导致他死掉  我只是...
got him killed, and I just, um...
至少这件事不是我的错
least that's one thing that's not my fault.
其实我想和你谈谈
Hey, I wanted to talk to you actually.
我觉得我理解你的感受
I think I understand how you're feeling.
有时候我们的能力太过奇特
Sometimes our powers are so extraordinary
它让我们的错误被放大了
it makes our mistakes feel amplified,
尤其会感到内疚
especially guilt.
是啊  但是我应该感觉内疚的
Yeah, but I should feel guilty.
我之前从来没有弄得这么糟糕过
I've never messed up this badly before,
我没法不去想
and I can't stop thinking about it.
这只是因为你在乎
That's just cause you care.
没事的  这是好事
It's okay. It's a good thing.
但是...
But...
诺拉  如果每次犯了错误
Nora, if every time you make a mistake
你都只是鲁莽地想去修复它
you just rush in to fix it
你只会把事情变得更糟
you're only gonna make things worse.
相信我  我比任何人都更懂这一点
Trust me, I know that better than anyone.
你只需要多一点点耐心
You just gotta have a little more patience.
花点时间
Take a moment.
三思而后行
Think before you act.
用正确的方法解决问题  好吗
Fix the problem the right way, all right?
好的
Okay.
听着  凯特琳  我很抱歉
Listen, Caitlin, I'm sorry.
为什么抱歉
For what?
为这一切抱歉
For all of this.
我就是觉得像一个彻头彻尾的笑话
Just I-I felt like a complete joke
劫持人质事件以后  歇洛克出现了
after that hostage thing, and then...Sherloque shows up
然后每个人都对他所谓的"侦探大师"着迷
and everybody swoons over his so-called "Master Detective-ness."
你好心邀请我一起来
You were nice enough to invite me along,
我还逼你去做那种事
and I pushed you... into that, and...
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
拉尔夫  你逼我去做的这件事
Ralph, this thing you pushed me into
给了我从来没有得到过的东西
gave me something I've never had before.
第一次犯下重罪吗
Your first felony?
不  是一个了结
No. Closure.
也许不太美好  但我终于知道了真相
It may not be pretty, but I finally know the truth.
这意味着一切
and that means everything.
对我来说
So, for my book,
你是一个女孩能找到的最好的侦探
you're the best detective a girl could ask for.
你一直没告诉我你妈妈那个
Hey, you never told me what the code was
《生化危机》死亡激光束房间的密码
on your mom's Resident Evil laser grid of death.
是我的生日
It was my birthday.
你一直没有喊叫
All this and not even a scream.
你以前经历过痛苦
You've experienced pain before,
但还不及我
but not more than me.
不  塞西尔  不要
No, Cecile don't.
不  这正是他想要的
No. That's what he wants.
我不想这样做
I didn't want to do this.
尤其是对一个有家室的人
Not to a family man.
但是我会的
But I will.
是时候作出决定了  韦斯特警探
Time to make a decision, Detective West.
趁你还活着的时候
While there's still some of you left.
不  不  不
No, no, no!
遇险警报
出什么事了
What's wrong?
他抓走了西斯科
He took Cisco!
蝉抓走了西斯科
Cicada took Cisco.
你说抓走了是什么意思  抓哪里去了
What do you mean took him? Took him where?
我不知道  我到的时候他们跳进了缺口
I don't know. They jumped into a breach right when I got here.
但是缺口可能把他们带去任何地方
But a breach could take them anywhere.
西斯科  能听到我吗
Cisco, can you hear me?
各位  你们听得到吗
Guys, can you hear me?
西斯科  你在哪
Cisco, where are you?
我不知道  我的缺口出了毛病
I don't know. My breach fritzed out
把我们扔在了某个森林里
and spat us out in a forest somewhere.
你能用缺口回来吗
Can you breach out?
不起作用
It's not working.
蝉在抑制他的能力
Cicada's dampening his powers.
没有卫星我无法确定他的位置
Without a satellite I can't pin point his location.
仅在这个州
I mean, in this state alone
就有超过一千四百万英亩森林
there's over 14 million acres of forest.
黑森林和罗阿诺克是最近的
All right, Black Forest and Roanoke are closest.
我从那里开始找
I'll start there.
我们没法及时找到他了  是吗
We're not gonna find him in time, are we?
在你们放弃之前  是什么树
Well, before you give up, what kind of trees?
什么
What?
森林里是什么种类的树  问问他
In the forest, what kind of trees, ask him.
西斯科  森林里的树是什么种类
Cisco, what kind of trees are they?
我不知道  我在森林里
I don't know! I'm in a forest!
什么种类的树  小家伙
What kind of trees, little one?
-我猜是松树  -很好
- Pine trees, I think. - Good.
有的树还有尖尖的叶子
Some of them have pointy leaves.
尖尖的  白蜡树  当然
Pointy.... ash trees, of course.
现在  我要你屏住呼吸
All right, now I need you to hold your breath.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
因为我要听森林里的声音
Because I need to hear the forest,
所以
So, shh.
蟋蟀
Crickets.
听到了吗  应该是田蟋蟀
You hear this? Assuming that's field crickets.
它们生活在土壤里
They live in the soil.
交叉对比田蟋蟀和有大量
Anyway, cross-reference field crickets with a high concentration
松树和白蜡树的野外地区  你会找出
of pine trees, ash trees, in an open field, and you have...
-科林斯森林  -马上过去
- Kolins Woods. - On my way!
巴里  你得离开那里
Barry, you got to get out of there!
我们得帮帮他
We have to help him.
巴里
Barry?
磨练技能是要花时间的  诺拉
It takes time to hone your skills, Nora.
你不能一步登天
You can't just skip rungs on the ladder
或是直接挑大梁  这是不行的
or jump right to the big stuff, that's not how it works.
花一点时间  行动之前先思考
Take a moment. Think before you act.
用正确的方法解决问题
Fix the problem the right way.
交给我吧
I got it.
我能解决这件事
I can fix this.
我已经想好了
I've thought this through.
我这次不会搞砸了
I won't mess it up this time.
我保证
I promise.
我相信你
I trust you.
去吧
Go.
中城这些年来
All these years in Central City
一直在维护超能力者  而不是消灭他们
spent defending metas instead of ending them.
那样的日子现在结束了
Those days end now.
从你开始
Starting with you.
用这个
Use this!
麦克尔·麦尔斯  来抑制这个吧
Hey, Michael Myers, dampen this.
警报
不  不  不
No. No. No. No.
西斯科死了
Cisco's gone.
我的天
Oh, my God--
西斯科
Cisco?
他还活着
He's alive.
对不起
Sorry.
你女儿
Your daughter.
她想起来不只有一种方法能打开缺口
She remembered there's more than one way to open a breach.
我想除非震波死了  蝉是不会放弃的
Figured Cicada wouldn't give up until Vibe was dead,
所以我们给他他想要的
so we gave him what he wanted.
多谢  脑残粉
Thanks, fangirl.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
我做得好吗
I did good?
你做得很棒
You did great.
震波死亡
看起来好像你真的死了
It's almost like you're really dead.
是啊
Yeah.
我的确差点死了
I almost really was.
我们到底要怎么抓住这个家伙
How the hell are we gonna catch this guy?
不能用我们的能力  至少我们知道这一点
Not with our powers. We know that at least.
我们也不知道其它的了
We don't know much else either.
时间线的变化  他们已经
Variations in the timeline, they've...
改变了元素  把公式变得更复杂
shifted the elements, complicated the equation.
-现在  -不是所有的元素都是不好的
- Now-- - Not all those elements are bad though.
你可能是拯救我们的新元素
You could be the new element that saves us.
你可能是我们抓住蝉的原因
You could be the reason we catch Cicada.
我必须得承认
I must admit,
诺拉小姐出其不意打中蝉那下
Miss Nora here pulled the rug right under from Cicada.
真是厉害的很哟
Woof, alley-oop, huh?
相当厉害
Very impressive.
那是我们这里会看到的唯一假死
Yeah, that's the only fake death we're gonna see around here
因为你要一直在这
'cause you're sticking around
直到把欠我们的都还回来
until you pay us back every cent.
我不得不说
Well, I have to say, prospect
想到要解另一个蝉之谜
of another mystery with Cicada
又给我添了动力
puts a little pep in my step.
还有那个你用来打开缺口
Also, that breach device you used to get
让你进出自如的装置
in and out of places, I suppose
现在已经锁在某个地方了吧
that's under lock and key right now?
那东西藏到海底了
That's at the bottom of the ocean
你这么想就行了
as far as you're concerned.
那我就留下了
Well, then I'm staying!
-太好了  -你当然要留下了
- Great! - Course you are.
我盯着你呢  福尔摩斯
I'm watching you, Holmes.
好吧  好吧  你会学到好多呢
Yes. Yes. Yes. Well, you'll learn a lot.
对你来是好事
Good for you.
好了  走吧  搭档
All right, shall we, sidekick.
我搭你脸的档
I'll sidekick your face.
我有预感  这俩人
Something tells me those two are gonna be
能成为好朋友
just great friends.
那...
So...
你俩今晚要家庭聚餐吗
You guys up for a family dinner night?
当然
Sure.
对  或许在那之后
Yeah. And then maybe after
我们可以帮你搬进阁楼
we could help you move into the loft.
我知道你在这儿有点孤独
I know you've been kind of cooped up here,
现在歇洛克需要住的地方
and now that Sherloque is gonna need a place to stay
我想你可以
I thought you could...
和我们一起住
crash with us.
我觉得不错  诺拉
I think it's a great idea, Nora.
好  谢谢啦  谢谢
Okay, thanks, yeah. Thanks.
我去拿我的包
Let me get my purse.
-好  -这蛮好的
- Okay. - This will be good.
我觉得这样可以
I think it could be just the thing
让你俩更亲近些
to bring you two closer together.
希望如此
I really hope so.
带西斯科出去喝一杯
Taking Cisco out for some drinks
纪念震波
in memoriam of Vibe.
-你要一起吗  -不了  谢谢
- You wanna come? - I'm okay, but thank you.
你想聊下吗
Anything you want to talk about?
我爸不是那种会写信的人
My dad wasn't really the letter writing type.
我觉得他会用其他方式来告诉我
I feel like he would have found some other way to tell me.
他的工作笔记里没有信息吗
No luck with his work notes?
没  这些分子模型都是乱七八糟的
No, I mean, these molecular models are gibberish.
到处都是空白  一些化合物根本就不存在
There's gaps everywhere and some of these compounds don't even exist.
就好像他的大脑先死掉了
It's like his mind was the first to go.
但或许我应该听我妈的
But, maybe I should just listen to my mom
忘掉过去
and forget about the past.
你落下这个了
You left this behind.
有时候过去是值得记住的
Sometimes the past is worth remembering.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯特琳的元素
它们不存在
They don't exist
是因为它们就不应该存在
because they're not supposed to.
凯特琳  来找我
这是我所能记起来
So this is all I could remember
有关蝉的全部  不多  但...
about Cicada. It's not much, but--
不不  这很好了
No. No. No, this is-- this is great.
每获得一些信息
I mean, every little bit we get
就能帮我们建立一个有关他的档案
helps build a profile on him.
我明早再梳理一下
I will comb over this in the morning.
你现在应该和塞西尔待在一起
You should go be with Cecile right now.
快好起来
Feel better.
等下  还有一件事
Wait. There's-- there's one more thing.
他做了有关家人的发言
He made these comments about family
他很珍视家人
and cherishing them.
还有他捡起詹娜毯子的方式
And then the way he picked up Jenna's blanket,
看着他的眼睛
and I got this feeling
我有一种感觉
when I looked in his eyes.
什么感觉
What--what kind of feeling?
我觉得蝉是位父亲
I think Cicada's a father.
你好  奥林
Hello, Orlin.
有进展吗
Any progress?
她没好转
She's not coming out of it.
让我看下
Let me see it.
这没愈合啊
It's not healing.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
你不能一直这样子
You can't keep doing this.
你必须得停下来
You have to stop.
等我完成之后
Not until I'm finished.
我来找我的钱包
I'm just looking for my purse.
我要和我父母一起吃饭
I'm about to have dinner with my parents.
在椅子上
It's on the chair.
在表层控制室里
In the Cortex.
人体模特边上
By the mannequin.
对  谢谢
Right. Thanks.
在这住得开心
Well, enjoy the couch.
诺拉
Nora.
你能帮我个忙吗
Can you help me with something?
我一直好奇
I've been wondering...
你  你回到你父母
You. You've traveled back into all these
生命中的重要时刻  对吧
great moments of your parent's lives, right?
有些很精彩  有些很危险
Some wonderful, some dangerous.
大多数都不像
Most not as dangerous as...
击打降落的卫星一样危险  对吧
punching a falling satellite, right?
然而
And yet...
就在那个时刻
that is the moment when you made
你下定决心去行动
the decision to act,
永远改变了历史的进程
altering the course of history forever.
那个决定
That decision...
是你自己做的吗
Did you come to it on your own?
当然是你自己做的
Of course you did!
对不  不  当然是你自己做的
Right? No, of course you did.
你是额外因素
You're Excess!
那诱惑
The temptation...
肯定相当之大
was too much, I'm sure.
的确是
It was.
好了
Well, please,
原谅我  你还要去吃饭呢
forgive me. You have a dinner to go to.
晚安
Good night.